Some missions are not a choice.
Mission: Impossible - Fallout is a action, adventure
film directed by Christopher McQuarrie.
When an IMF mission ends badly, the world is faced with dire consequences.
As Ethan Hunt takes it upon himself to fulfill his original briefing,
the CIA begin to question his loyalty and his motives.
The IMF team find themselves in a race against time, hunted by
assassins while trying to prevent a global catastrophe.
Ethan Hunt, played by Tom Cruise.
August Walker, played by Henry Cavill.
Luther Stickell, played by Ving Rhames.
Benji Dunn, played by Simon Pegg.
Ilsa Faust, played by Rebecca Ferguson.
Solomon Lane, played by Sean Harris.
Mission: Impossible – Fallout is a 2018 American action spy film
written and directed by Christopher McQuarrie.
It is the sequel to Mission: Impossible – Rogue Nation (2015) and the
sixth installment in the Mission: Impossible film series.
The ensemble cast includes Tom Cruise, Henry Cavill, Ving Rhames, Simon Pegg, Rebecca Ferguson,
Sean Harris, Angela Bassett, Vanessa Kirby, Michelle Monaghan, and Alec Baldwin.
Set two years after the events of Rogue Nation, Fallout follows Impossible Missions Force agent Ethan Hunt (Cruise) and his team in
their efforts to prevent a nuclear attack by terrorist Solomon Lane (Harris) and the mysterious extremist John Lark.
Work on a sequel to Rogue Nation commenced before its 2015 release.
The series' first returning director, McQuarrie intended for Fallout to better explore Ethan's character and emotions, believing previous entries
had left him primarily a cipher for audiences, and to test the limits of Ethan's abilities, morality, and personal relationships.
The script was brief, only 33 pages, serving as an outline driven primarily by the interesting filming
locations and allowing for improvisation and significant changes to scenes throughout filming.
Principal photography began in April 2017, on a $178–180 million budget, in Paris, continuing
on to London, New Zealand, Norway, and the United Arab Emirates by early 2018.
Filming was delayed for several months after Cruise broke his ankle during a stunt, significantly inflating the budget while the
production waited for his return but also providing McQuarrie the opportunity to further develop unfinished scenes in the script.
Mission: Impossible – Fallout premiered in Paris on July 12, 2018, and
was theatrically released in the United States on July 27.
The film garnered universal acclaim, particularly for its
standout setpieces, and received several awards.
It also broke box office records for the series and grossed $791.1 million worldwide, making it the
highest-grossing film in the Mission: Impossible series and the eighth-highest-grossing film of 2018.
Fallout was followed by two sequels: Mission: Impossible – Dead Reckoning Part
One (2023) and Mission: Impossible – The Final Reckoning (2025).
The film explores themes of mask, race against time, london,
england, central intelligence agency (cia), helicopter.